So to do that, I created this little function that I called create_date,
我创建了一个函数 叫做 create_date
and I just created it as a Lambda function.
并设为 Lambda 函数
Essentially, I said I'm going to pull the last parts.
我将提取最后部分
So, you can imagine,
可以想象
this is just pulling this last part off,
这段代码会提取最后一部分
and we can try to pull an example.
可以尝试提取一个示例
But there are some of these movies that don't have this,
但是有些电影没有这部分
but I'm going to essentially just look for this last part,
我将查找最后这一部分
and there could be tricky parts if,
可能有点难
let me go check this afterwards,
稍后我再检查一下
but I'm just going to look for this last parentheses.
我将查看最后这个小括号
Basically, if that exist,
如果存在的话
I want to pull the date from it,
我将从中提取日期
and if it doesn't exist, then I don't want to.
如果不存在 则不希望提取日期
So, if this last part is equal to one of these parentheses,
如果最后一部分等于这个小括号
then I want to pull the date,
那么我将提取日期
and otherwise I'm just going to give a name.
否则设为 nan
So, otherwise, I'm going to say, there isn't a date associated with it.
表示没有相关日期
I'm going to create a new date column,
我将创建一个新的列 date
and I'm going to apply this function to the movies column,
将此函数应用到 movies 列上
and then just take a look.
然后看看结果
I made a mistake somewhere.
哪里出错了
Sorry. This should be X.
抱歉这个应该为 x
This is the next movies.
然后是 movies
I think it's called movie.
应该叫做 movie
Yeah. So, the column itself is called movie and this was an X.
Yeah列本身叫做 movie 这个是 x
So, basically, we are going into that movie column and we're
我们将转到 movie 列
applying this function that looks for this ending mark.
应用此函数并寻找此结束标记
If it exist, then it pulls this date using this part,
如果存在 则根据这部分提取日期
and otherwise it should have a name.
否则设为 nan
Essentially, what we want to do is I think the date will be easiest.
我认为日期最简单
I'm going to create a little function again,
再创建一个函数
I'll call it add_movie_year,
叫做 add_movie_year()
and it's just going to take in some value.
向其传入一个值
So, you can imagine, again,
可以想象
we're going to apply this function to each one of these,
我们将向它们应用此函数
and what we want to do is we want to pull the first two parts.
我们将提取前两部分
So now, I'm going to pull the first two characters,
提取前两个字符
and then if they're equal to some value a year, I'll return.
如果等于某个年份 返回 1
So, if, then I'll return a one,
将这部分放入 if-else 块中
and else, I'll return zero.
否则返回 0
So, essentially, this little function is going to look at these first two letters.
这个函数将查看前两个字母
I'll pass in a list of these things,
我将传入这个列表
and we'll loop through them,
遍历这些列表项
and then apply this to create a new column.
然后应用此函数并创建新的列
So, the dates are basically either a 18, a 19,
日期是 18 或 19
or a 2000,
或 20 开头
and I'm going to
我将为每项
create a new column for each one of those that's just going to be named after the year.
创建一个新的列 以年份命名
So, essentially, what this is doing is it's creating
这行代码将创建一个新的列名称
a new column name that we're attaching onto the movies data set,
并附加到 movies 数据集上
and it's going to be named 1800s, 1900s,
命名为 1800s 1900s 或 2000s
or 2000s, and we just want to apply to
我们将 add_movie_year 函数
the current date column this add_movie_year function.
应用到当前的 date 列
So, this is going to take the function and apply it to this,
这行代码会将该函数应用到此列上
which is just going to get back a one or a zero,
返回 1 或 0
and it'll do that for every value in date.
并对 date 中的每个值都运行一遍
So, this should do this as an array where it gives back a one or a zero,
应该会形成数组 返回一个 1 或 0
and then we're just going to basically put that onto the end of our data set again.
然后放到数据集的后面
Great. So, if we look at this,
Great看看运行结果
you can see that all of these movies are in 1800s.
所有这些电影都属于 1800 年代
For the last part that we want to do with this,
最后一部分是
we want to create a dummy column for the genre.
为类型创建一个虚拟列
The genre is a little tricky to work with because there
类型比较难处理
can be more than one, as we can see here,
因为可能属于不同的类型
like I should have a documentary and a short,
例如这个即是纪录片 又是短片
and this one should have a short and a horror.
这个即是短片 又是惊悚片
Then basically, you can imagine,
可以想象
like we found up above,
就像这里显示的一样
we have 28 genres.
有 28 种类型
So, essentially, what we want to have onto the end of our data frame is 28 genres
我们要在 DataFrame 后面列出 28 种类型
listed with either a one if that genre is associated with that movie or a zero otherwise.
如果电影属于该类型 则输入 1 否则输入 0
So, the first thing I'm going to do is I'm just going to create
首先 我将创建一个方法
this thing that's going to split the genres.
它会拆分 genres
It's going to take this part,
它会接受这一部分
and just going to split them, and give it back to us.
然后拆分它们 并返回结果
We actually could use something similar to what we did above,
我们可以采用和上面相似的方法
but there's this nice function we can show how that works.
但是我将演示一个很方便的函数
So, if we look at movies.genre 0, so that looks like this.
输入 movies.genre[0]
If we do find short,
运行 find(‘short’)
it gives us the index and the index of the first place of that genre.
它会返回该类型第一次出现时的索引
If we do the same thing, but let's say,
再查找一次
we do horror and horror isn't in here,
但是查找 horror 没有 horror
so it gives us a negative one if it's not found.
返回 -1 表示没找到
So, we can use that to look for each of the genres.
我们可以这么查找类型
So, what we can do is we can take the list of genres that we created up here,
传入在这里创建的类型列表
this group of genres.
即这组类型
We're going to say, for g and genres,
输入 for g in genres;
and then we're going to loop through,
遍历这个列表
and see if that's in there.
看看是否存在某个类型
If it is, then we'll return a one,
如果存在 则返回 1
and else, we'll return a zero.
否则返回 0
We still have to look out for those null values
依然需要注意 Null 值
and basically those will give us an attribute error.
Null 值会导致属性错误
So, I'm going to write in this except statement.
将这部分放入 except 语句中
Well, I'm just going to call them zeros,
我直接称之为 0
you could return an n here too.
你也可以返回 nan
I'm just going to return them as zeros and basically say,
我将返回 0
you didn't list any genre,
表示你没有列出任何类型
so I'm just going to give it zero for all of the genres,
所以我将对所有类型输出 0
which may or may not be the best way to actually do that.
这或许是最好的处理方式 或许不是
Then, I'm just going to add a column for each genre,
然后我将为每种类型添加一列
and we can do this by taking the existing genre column,
我们可以使用现有的 genre 列
and applying our split genres function.
并应用 split_genres 函数
So, we're going to apply this function to each one of these things,
我们将此函数应用到这里的每一项上
and then this will create an array,
这样会创建一个数组
and then we're just going to attach that on for each one of those genres.
向数组中附加每个类型
If we look at, wait, sorry.
如果我们查看...抱歉
We don't want this to be a find.
这里不能是 find()
It doesn't return a true or false,
它不返回 true 或 false
it returns a number.
返回一个数字
So, basically, if it returns a number that's greater than negative one,
如果返回的数字大于 -1
because when it moves through this genre,
因为它会遍历这个类型
like this is the zero index,
这里是索引 0
this is the one index,
这里是索引 1
this is the two index,
这里是索引 2
this is the three index,
这里是索引 3
it's going to give us some number between zero and the length of this string minus one.
返回的数字将在 0 到这个字符串的长度减一之间
So, basically, if it's any positive number or zero,
如果是任何正数或零
what we know is that it exists in that genre string.
则表明存在于该类型字符串中
If it's a negative one,
如果是 -1
it's not even possible that it's less than that.
不可能小于 -1
But if it is greater than negative one, we know it exists.
如果大于 -1 则表示存在
If it is negative one,
如果是 -1
then we know it doesn't exist.
则表示不存在
So, this is one way we could do it.
这是一种代码实现方式
We could probably think of some other ways as well.
或许还有其他方式
Then, the mistake is in my header.
我的标题出错了
Just don't like seeing that error, and this code works.
不喜欢看到这个错误 这段代码能运行
So now, we can see this thing tacked onto the end.
可以看到后面有好几列
It looks like there's a lot of zeros that I can see.
看到了好多的 0
Let's make sure.
我们改一改 使这里...
Yeah. Let's make sure that there's one in here.
Yeah使这里出现一个 1
Come on. Great. Yeah. So, there's a one here and there's a one here,
还不行啊GreatYeah这里有个 1 这里有个 1
which is consistent with what we saw before.
与之前看到的一致
One of the things that we'll need when we're working with
使用这些时间戳时
these timestamps is this datetime library.
我们需要使用这个 datetime 库
With a quick search,
快速搜索下
and I just searched timestamp to date in Python,
我搜索了 timestamp to date python
and with that quick search,
快速搜索后
this first link that you find will actually show you the thing that I used,
第一个链接将显示我采用的这个方法
which is this fromtimestamp,
也就是这个 fromtimestamp
and then you're changing things into a year,
然后将日期变成
month, day, hour, minute, second.
年 月 日 时 分 秒
By using this, I can create this little function,
通过它可以创建这个函数
and so I just called it change_timestamp,
称之为 change_timestamp
and what it's going to do is it's going to take this timestamp.
它将接受这个时间戳
Using the library, there's
使用这个库
a fromtimestamp where I want to take the integer of this thing,
在 fromtimestamp 中接受这项的整数形式
so it needs to be as a number and I think originally,
它必须是数字
it was as a string,
原来是字符串
and then I want to change it into
然后使用看到的相同方法
a string with basically the same thing that we saw back here.
将它变成字符串
I really just want this part here and I'm going to change this part here.
我只要这部分 并且我将更改此部分
So, I think that should be a function that we can now apply to this timestamp column.
现在我们可以将此函数应用到这个 timestamp 列了
Okay. So, let's take a look.
Ok看看运行效果
Great. So now, you can see we've changed that timestamp into this date_time.
Great可以看出 我们将该 timestamp 变成了这个 date_time